(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-16T10:18:57.739879",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ
It's time to shine!
呼び合う声を 合図に
Taking our cue from each other's calls,
Parade, Parade, Parade!
探しに行く
We go search for it!
スタートは何度だって
No matter how many times we start over.
ただ 独り言 呟いた
I just muttered to myself.
ただ 始まりたくて 走った
I just ran because I wanted it to begin.
遠く 暗がりに灯った
Lit up far away in the gloom,
それは 眩し過ぎた 名前
It was a name that shone too bright.
それは 優し過ぎる 思い出 もっと
It's a memory so gentle, even more...
近づけと 手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand to get closer.
思いがけず 結び合った
Unexpectedly, we became bound together.
ほら 今 迷子は「僕 等」になった
Look, now the lost ones have become "us."
輝くんだよ
It's time to shine!
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいで
Bring your regrets and your love along with you.
風、夢、羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, and feathers, you can take flight!
ささやかな祈りは 光 終わりなし 兆し
Humble prayers are light, an endless omen.
君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
I can hold my head high for finding you.
Our Bright Parade, Parade!
まだ 頼りない 予感を
Still with uncertain premonitions,
歌おう 恥ずかしくなんかないよ
Let's sing, there's nothing to be ashamed of!
誰も 解けない イマジナリー
An imaginary thing no one can solve,
いつか また 逢える おまじない
A spell so we can meet again someday.
あの日 ゼロに始まった ストーリー
The story that began at zero on that day,
数え切れ ない 言の葉
Words too numerous to count.
数えるような 想いじゃないさ
It's not a feeling you can just count.
ほら 今 「僕 等」を一つと呼ぼう
Look, now let's call "us" one.
Parade, Parade, Parade!
美しいんだよ
It's so beautiful!
見交わした ビジとわ 君と歩くことさ
The vision we exchanged is walking with you.
ただいま を聞けば
When I hear "I'm home",
おかえり って叫ぶよ
I shout "Welcome back!"
当たり前じゃないか
Of course it is!
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ 暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ
Filling the darkness are you and I!
君と歩くことなんだ
It's walking with you.
ただ今を聴けば
If we listen right now,
おかえりって叫ぶよ
We'll shout "Welcome back!"
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that only natural?
Parade, Parade, Parade!
輝くんだよ
It's time to shine!
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ
Filling the darkness are you and I!
Parade, parade, parade!
輝くんだよ 呼び合う声を 合図に
It's time to take the stage, I hear the voices calling out your name.
Parade, parade, parade! 探しにゆく
Parade, parade, parade! A new journey awaits,
スタートは何度だって
just hit reset and we can start again.
ただ 独り言を綴った
I weave lonely words into echoes,
ただ 始まりたくて走った
I run because I heard a voice say, "Go."
遠く 暗がり 燈した
Far away, lighting up all the darkness,
それは 眩し過ぎた名前
it's a name shining for us to notice.
それは 優し過ぎる思い出もずっと
Memories that fill us up with kindness and love,
近付けと 手を伸ばした
you reach out and tell me to come close.
思いがけず 結び合った
Let's surprise people who don't know,
ほら 今 迷子 は “僕 等” に なった
every one that they called "the lost"...
Parade, parade, parade! 輝くんだよ
Here we are as "us". Parade, parade, parade!
Parade, parade, parade! It's time to take the stage.
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Couldn't beat her smile, it stirred up all the media.
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
Secret side, I wanna know it so mysterious.
抜け出してる とこさえ彼女のエリア
Even that elusive side, part of her controlled area.
完璧で嘘つきな君は
Complete and perfect, all you say is a bunch of lies,
天才的なアイドル様
Dear miss genius idol, unmatched.
アイドル 作詞・作曲:Ayase
[Song: Idol / Lyrics & Music: Ayase]
今日何食べた?
What did you eat today?
好きな本は?
What book do you love?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの?
Whenever you go out for fun, tell me, where do you go?
何も食べてない
Haven't eaten anything.
それは内緒
It's a secret, unknown.
何を聞かれてものらりくらり
Any questions you're facing, always acting so vaguely,
淡々とだけど燦々と
so unconcerned, although you brightly glow.
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
Any seemingly unveiled secrets are as sweet as honey.
あれもないないない これもないないない
Confusing, why, why, why? Essential lie, lie, lie.
好きなタイプは? 相手は? さあ答えて
So, what is your type of guy? Any partner? Answer this.
「誰かを好きになることなんて私分からないからさ」
"I don't have any idea how I could love anyone."
嘘か本当か知り得ない
"I don't seem to know what it signifies."
そんな言葉にまた一人堕ちる
Cannot find out if it's true or it's a lie.
また好きにさせる
Once again, there's somebody who's fallen for the words,
誰もが目を奪われていく
That emotion melts all hearts, all eyes on you.
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
'Cause you are perfect, the most ultimate idol,
金輪際現れない
Unrivaled, will not appear again.
一番星の生まれ変わり
It's the brightest star reborn, yes, indeed.
その笑顔で愛してるで
Ah, using that smiling face, that "I love you" again.
誰も彼も虜にしていく
Now, everybody is lured and captivated by you,
その瞳がその言葉が
The pupil that you got, the words you vocalize.
嘘でもそれは完璧なアイ
Even when untrue, it's your perfected AI.
はいはいあの子は特別です
Right, right, we all know she's very special, yes.
我々はハナからおまけです
We had lost the fight before it started, so impressed,
お星さまの引き立て役Bです
We're serving as support to her grace.
全てがあの子のお陰なわけない
Cannot tell me everything was because of her.
洒落臭い 嫉妬妬みなんてないわけがない
How can we not feel jealous while being around?
これはネタじゃないからこそ許せない
It's not a joke, you know, right? So, I cannot forgive you.
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない
Completely deny, imperfect you that I sight,
自分を許せない
Myself, no pardon allowed.
誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I won't allow anyone if it's not you, strongest of all.
誰もが信じ崇めてる
That emotion seized all hearts worshiping you, yes, indeed.
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
So strong, it's you, unrivaled idol.
弱点なんて見当たらない
There cannot be weaknesses to find,
一番星を宿している
The brightest star is residing in you.
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
The gaps and shortcomings, don't show 'em, dammit, dammit.
知られたくないとこは隠して
Parts nobody wants to know should remain hidden.
唯一無二なんてさ
One and only, if it's different, no way, no way.
言え言えそれこそ本物のアイ
Such a true love, it's the realest AI.
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
Showing this smile, my own weapon boiling media.
隠し切るこの秘密だけは
Keeping everything about my secret deep inside.
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
"I'm in love with you," my career is built on such a lie.
これこそ私なりの愛だ
It's the way I know to show my love, without a doubt.
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Running down, my sweat is flowing, cleanest aqua, right?
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
Ruby hidden under my eyelids where it resides.
歌い踊る私はマリア
I sing and dance around, look at me, I'm Maria.
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
So, lying surely is the greatest kind of love.
誰かに愛されたことも
I recall no one that loved me whole before.
誰かのこと愛したこともない
And I've not been in love with anybody before.
そんな私の嘘がいつか本当になること
Now, the lies I'm making up, I'm hoping that a day comes
信じている
when they all become true, and I keep wishing they do.
いつかきっと全部手に入れる
One day, I will hold everything that I pursue.
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
Yes, I am so greedy, true voracious idol.
等身大でみんなのこと
So, sincerely, what I'm wishing for is to love
ちゃんと愛したいから
each of you with all my heart.
今日も嘘をつくの
And so, today, I lie again.
この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って
The words I vocalize inside of me, I'm wishing that one day they come true.
それでもまだ
Up to this day, I've not been able to let you...
君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
And you hear me saying those meaningful words.
ああやっと言えた
I, I said it at last.
これは絶対嘘じゃない愛してる
I know it's not a lie as I'm voicing these words, I love you.
愛してる
I love you.
はーい！ってことで、始まりました！みんな！
Alright! With that said, it's finally started, everyone!
このLamy Love Festにお越しの
Welcome to Lamy Love Fest,
ホロライブ5期生の雪花ラミィです！
I am Yukihana Lamy from Hololive 5th Generation!
ラミィちゃんしか！愛せな…
Only Lamy-chan can... love...
あいしてるのはらみちゃーということで
What I love is Lamy-chan... So,
ありがとうみんな！
thank you everyone!
え、今回のえ、柱はこちら！
Um, our main feature this time is...
雪花ラミィ 3周年ライブとなっております！
Yukihana Lamy's 3rd Anniversary Live!
そしてこの後ろのモニターに映っている
And, shown on the monitor behind me,
ラミィラブフェスト！ こちらね、
"Lamy Love Fest!" Right here,
この名前のとおり、今日のライブはラミィの大好きをたっぷり詰め込んだお祭りとなっています！
just as the name says, today's live is a festival packed with everything Lamy loves!
これからゲストパートに入るわけなんですけれども
We're about to enter the guest part,
ラミィの大好きなホロメンとラミィがずっと出たかったあんな曲やこんな曲を一緒に踊って歌ってやっていきたいと思います！
and together with Holomembers Lamy loves, we'll sing and dance to songs Lamy has always wanted to perform!
そして今日はみんな！街に待ったあの子が登場でーす！
And today, everyone! The girl we've all been waiting for is making her entrance!
さあ、雪民さん！
Now then, Yukimin!
あーかわいい！みんな見て見て！
Ah, so cute! Everyone, look, look!
ついに雪花ラミィ 3周年記念にして、雪民さんが3Dで登場しました！みんな見て！ほら！
At last, for Yukihana Lamy's 3rd anniversary, Yukimin has appeared in 3D! Everyone look! See?
あーかわいい！かわいい！
Ah, so cute! So cute!
よしよし、いこいこ。お姉ちゃんちょっと、ほらほらほら。
There, there, come here. Hey big sis, look, look, look.
雪民さんね、ちょっとあの、いいの？ねぇちゃっても。今からライブ見るんじゃないの？一緒に応援してくれるんじゃないの？えっ？
Yukimin, wait, is that okay? Even if you're my big sis? Aren't you going to watch the live? Aren't you going to cheer together? Huh?
起きて、起きて起きて！起きて起きて起きて起きて起きて起きて起きて！
Wake up, wake up, wake up! Wake up, wake up, wake up, wake up, wake up!
起きて、雪民さん起きて！よかった、安心したよ。
Wake up, Yukimin, wake up! Thank goodness, I'm relieved.
じゃね、雪民さんも起きたところで、今回ね、みんな1曲目で気づいてると思うけど、これ、見てください！どーん！
Well then, now that Yukimin is awake, I think everyone noticed from the first song, but look at this! Ta-da!
雪花ラミィ アイドルステージができました！いぇーい！
Yukihana Lamy's idol stage is complete! Yay!
よいしょ。こんなね、雪花ラミィのステージもこだわりがいっぱい詰まっているんですよってことで、ちょっとね、紹介していきたいと思いますけれども。
Yoisho. This Yukihana Lamy stage is packed with attention to detail, so let me introduce it to you.
まず、見てください！こだわりのバルーンアートと、えー、ツウィルの姿となっております！
First, look at this! Balloon art and Twill's appearance!
いや、かわいいでしょ、これ！
Isn't this cute, right?
そしてこっちには、じゃーん！大福がペンライトを振ってくれていまーす！かわいい！大福も大きくなったなー。
And over here, ta-da! Daifuku is waving a glow stick for us! So cute! Daifuku has grown so big.
そしてこっちには、雪民さんが大きいのと、中くらいのと、小さいのの三兄弟がペンライトを振って応援してくれてます！
And over here, three brothers of Yukimin—large, medium, and small—are waving glow sticks to cheer us on!
そして、みんなほら！見えるかな？これこれこれこれ！これも、え、ツウィルの形を、いま付けてないけど、ツウィルのね、形をモニターにしていただきました！
And everyone, look! Can you see? This, this, this! They even made a monitor shaped like Twill for us!
雪民さんほら、あ、映ってるよ雪民さん！映ってるよ！えー！
Look, Yukimin, ah, you're on screen, Yukimin! You're on screen! Yay!
というね、もうこのこだわりのステージ。いや本当にラミィ3周年にしてこんなにいろんなことがね、あの起きてしまう、いきなり起きてしまったのでラミィもちょっとついていけてないところはありますけれども。
So, this meticulously crafted stage. Truly, for Lamy's 3rd anniversary, so many things suddenly happened, so Lamy is still trying to keep up.
このあとは、ついにゲストパート！そして最後は、みんなを楽しみしているあれが来るかも知れません！
After this, finally the guest part! And at the very end, something everyone is looking forward to might come!
ってことでね、みんな行きますか？ゲストパートレッツの前に、らむまーえ！いってきまーす！
So everyone, shall we go? Before the guest part "Let's", Lamy... off we go!
森羅万象の悪戦苦闘も マヨネーズかけたら大体美味しくなる？
Even the struggles of creation can be delicious with mayonnaise?
君が泣いてお腹は空くよ
Even if you cry, you get hungry.
消化できなかった「ごめん ごめん。」
An undigested "Sorry, sorry."
森羅万象の悪戦苦闘も
Even the hardest thing in all the world,
マヨネーズかければ大体おいしくなる？
if you put mayonnaise on it, will it taste good?
君が泣いてもお腹は空くよ
Even if you cry, you'll still get hungry.
消化できなかったごめんごめん
I couldn't digest it, sorry, sorry.
酸いも甘いも勝手に食べて
Sour things, sweet things, I'll eat 'em all I want.
ご迷惑をおかけしています
Very sorry to trouble you so.
パクチー置いて変な味のジュース
Cilantro arrangement, weird-flavored juice,
心を無にして飲み込みます ah！
ignoring my heart, I gulp it down, ah!
ああ 混沌情報過多のレストランで
At the restaurant, chaotic information overload,
嘘っぱちのメニューにお茶こぼして
spilled my tea on the lying menu.
君と もぐもぐ (もぐもぐ) もぐもぐ (もぐもぐ)
With you, mogu mogu, mogu mogu...
銃撃戦の真ん中で もぐもぐ
Right in the middle of a firefight, mogu mogu.
(うぎゃー)
(Ugya!)
魑魅魍魎ハラペコの群れ
Group of starving mountain demons,
満腹になる未来を願っているよ もぐもぐ
I'm hoping for a future where I'm full, mogu mogu.
(もぐもぐ) もぐもぐ (もぐもぐ)
Mogu mogu...
世界が終わる前に もぐもぐ
Before the world ends, mogu mogu.
やみい マジ神 やむやむ ありのまんま もぐもぐ
Yami, maji, kami, yam yam, as it is, mogu mogu.
やみい magic coming この世を味わうんだ うまうま
Yami, magic coming, tasting this world, yum yum.
理論武装のミルフィーユサンド
Theoretically backed mille-feuille sandwich,
匿名希望のオーロラソース
wishing to be anonymous aurora sauce.
大雑把な味付け多めに見てよ
Roughly seasoned, but overlook it.
おいしくなったらオッケーオッケー
If it's tasty, it's ok, ok.
良いモン悪いモンいっぱい食べて
Good things, bad things, eat lots,
汚れた口元拭います
I'll wipe my dirty mouth.
おにぎり ピザ ケーキ 豪華なフルコース
Rice ball, pizza, cake, extravagant full course meal,
罠を疑い気をつきます ah！
questioning if it's a trap, I'll be careful, ah!
妄想流言飛語のバイキングで
Wild ideas, groundless rumors of a buffet,
毒入りと絶品料理選び分けて
sorting between rotten food and high class cooking.
君と もぐもぐ (もぐもぐ) もぐもぐ (もぐもぐ)
With you, mogu mogu, mogu mogu...
デスゲームの教室で もぐもぐ
In a death game classroom, mogu mogu.
魑魅魍魎ハラペコの群れ
Group of starving mountain demons,
仲のいい君と生き残れたらいいな もぐもぐ
it'd be nice if you, my good friend, would survive, mogu mogu.
(もぐもぐ) もぐもぐ (もぐもぐ)
Mogu mogu...
数年後もこの場所で もぐもぐ
In a few years at this place, mogu mogu.
やみい マジ神 今夜の晩ごはんは もぐもぐ
Yami, maji, kami, tonight's dinner will be mogu mogu.
やみい magic coming 次はお前の番だ もぐもぐ
Yami, magic coming, next time will be your turn, mogu mogu.
やみい マジ神 やむやむ ありのまんま もぐもぐ
Yami, maji, kami, yam yam, as it is, mogu mogu.
やみい magic coming この世を味わうんだ うまうま
Yami, magic coming, tasting this world, yum yum.
もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐ
Mogu mogu, mogu mogu...
もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐやみい
Mogu mogu, mogu mogu yami!
もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐ
Mogu mogu, mogu mogu...
もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐやみい
Mogu mogu, mogu mogu yami!
もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐ
Mogu mogu, mogu mogu...
もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐやみい
Mogu mogu, mogu mogu yami!
もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐ
Mogu mogu, mogu mogu...
もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐ もぐもぐやみい やみい
Mogu mogu, mogu mogu yami, yami!
ラミィさん周年おめでとう！
Happy 3rd anniversary!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
なぬっ！？ ビシッ おりゃっ！ バシッ
What's this?! A bishi-bori strike!
ツッコミも冴えて 本日快晴
With witty comebacks, it's clear skies today!
さぁっ ボロ… ぎゅむっ バキッ 手にする全部 it's mine! くれくれ
Grab it all, it's mine, give it here!
適度にがんばろっか (そっか？)
Work hard in moderation? (Really?)
そんなんだっていいけどさ
No matter what they say, that's fine.
必死にがんばろっか (そうだ！)
Work hard with all your might? (That's right!)
それが僕らしいよな
That's just the way we are.
ダサすぎじゃねえんだわ！
Isn't that totally lame?
そんで貧乏っちいじゃねえんだわ！
And totally impoverished, right?
うんっ 万事がバッチリいけてるに決まってるっ！
Yeah! Everything's going swimmingly, as expected!
(are you?) かなたちゃん
(Are you?) Kanata-chan!
どどん！ 前進上等！ ちゃんと歓迎して
Full speed ahead! Welcome them properly!
(wonder-la-der-la) 高まれ
(Wonder-la-der-la) Raise it high!
海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して
Create sea and sky, and be amazed!
(wonder-la-der-la) 興奮しようよ
(Wonder-la-der-la) Let's get excited!
ボクが言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん 現実超えろ未来 あー！
I mean it, I'm really going to do it! Let's surpass reality, ah!
弱点も平気 スイッチでランチャー！
No problem with weaknesses, switch to launcher!
(wonder-la-der-la) すなわち 特者生存ワンダランダDAY
(Wonder-la-der-la) That is, Tokusetsu Survival Wonderland Day!
(wonder-la-der-la) 楽しもうよ
(Wonder-la-der-la) Let's have fun!
面白がれること探したまえ over？ 返事聞かせてくれ！
Find interesting things to do, over? Let me hear your reply!
左右なんかじゃない (かなたーうんっ！)
Not just left or right (Kanata-oo-n!)
決めつけて一直線 (かなたーうんっ！)
Aiming straight ahead (Kanata-oo-n!)
つまり企んだら発射オーライだ
If you plan it out, it's all systems go!
ワクワクすんぜ！ しゃー！
I'm getting so excited! Yeah!
「聞いて！！」
"Listen!!"
「推しイベきちい あああ アイドル オタク 楽しい～！ でも」
"Oshi events are great, idols and otaku are so fun! But..."
「ガッチャ※※の結婚は立ち直れてません」
"Gaccha *censored* marriage isn't happening."
「ガチャだ！！ 出るまで回せば100%ピックアップ！！」
"It's a gacha!! Spin until you get it for 100% pickup!!"
「ｗｗｗｗ 天井でーす ｗｗｗｗ」
"Lololol, in your dreams!!"
「何だよそんなこと言いちゃダメだ、おばか！」
"Why would you say something so terrible, grandma?!"
「うわ～ すごい！ ありがとう～」
"Whoa, amazing! Thanks a bunch~"
日々これ騒然で go my way!
Day in, day out, let's go my way!
虎視眈々といたいんだもん
Living with a wary eye on everything.
だって意気ガンガンがいいんだもん
Because a strong will is what I want.
全方位にがっちりアンテナ張ってなくちゃっ！
You've got to keep your antennas up in all directions!
いつでも心はちゃんと純真でいたいな
I always want my heart to be pure and innocent,
好奇心は絶えず熱心でいたいなって
and my curiosity to remain ever passionate.
言い聞かせるんだ 調子に乗ったら
I tell myself, once you catch momentum,
すぐ飽いられちゃうから あー！
you'll get bored right away, ah!
タイトなロープもどんとこいでっせ
Tie a tight knot in the rope.
すなわち 特者生存ワンダランダDAY しがみつき
That is, Tokusetsu Survival Wonderland Day! Keep in mind:
“努力とは最後まで諦めないこと” メモっておいて！
"Effort means never giving up until the very end."
ホントは baby 自信なんてないよ
Truth is, baby, I don't have any confidence.
ホントは baby 不安ばかりで泣きそうだ
Truth is, baby, I'm so anxious I could cry.
でもね baby 挫けないって決めたの
But you know, baby, I decided not to give up.
だから baby 挑戦したいよ 未開の天地 無限のフィールドで！
So, baby, I want to challenge myself in uncharted lands and infinite fields!
前進上等！ ちゃんと歓迎して 高まれ
Full speed ahead! Welcome them properly and raise it high!
海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して 興奮しようよ
Create sea and sky, and be amazed! Let's get excited!
ボクが言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
I mean it, I'm really going to do it!
現実超えろ未来 あー！
Let's surpass reality, ah!
弱点も平気 スイッチでランチャー！
No problem with weaknesses, switch to launcher!
すなわち 特者生存ワンダランダDAY 楽しもうよ
That is, Tokusetsu Survival Wonderland Day! Let's have fun!
面白がれること探し放題でっせ 無限のフィールドで
Find interesting things to do to your heart's content in this infinite field!
パンピングしなくてもいい (かなたーうんっ！)
You don't even have to panick (Kanata-oo-n!)
ど真ん中一直線 (かなたーうんっ！)
Right down the middle, straight ahead! (Kanata-oo-n!)
つまりこれが僕の答えなんだ
That's right, this is my answer.
胸を張れ！ 今を生きるその意味を
Stand tall and proud! Understand the meaning of living in the present!
明くる日も明くる来る日も確かめ進め！ おうりゃー！
Check out the dawning days and marching days, and push forward! Oh, all-clear!
なにっ!? ビシッ お利口っちゃ! バシッ
What?! Bam! Such a good girl! Whack!
ツッコミも冴えて 本日快晴
Sharp retorts too, today is clear skies!
さわっ… ボロ… ぎゅむっ… バキッ
Touch... worn out... squeeze... crack!
手にする全部 It's mine! くれくれ
Everything I get is mine! Give it!
適度にながんばろっか (そっか?)
Work moderately hard, right? (Is that so?)
そんなんだっていいけどさ
That's fine too, but y'know
天上で…
Up in the heavens...
推しイベきちゃあああ アイドルオタク楽しい～！
My favorite event is here! Idol otaku is fun~!
でもガチ恋の結婚は立ち直ってません
But I can't recover from oshi's marriage!
ガチャだ！！出るまで回せば100%ピックアップ！！
Gacha! Spin till you get 100% pickup!
ｗｗｗｗ 天井 でーす ｗｗｗｗ
Lolol, it's pity system lolol
何だよそんなこと言っちゃダメだろ、おまか！
What're you saying, don't say that, you idiot!
うわっ すごい あいりる ～ ちゃ ！
Wow, what an awesome idol!
日々これ騒然で go my way!
Days are bustling like this, go my way!
虎視眈々でいたいんだもん
I want to be watchful and vigilant
だって意気意気ガンガンがいいんだもん
Because going all out with high spirit is great!
全方位にがっつりアンテナ張ってなくちゃ！
Gotta set antennas firmly in all directions!
いつでも心はちゃんと純粋で
Always keeping my heart pure
いたいな
It hurts, it hurts...
好奇心は絶えず熱心で
Curiosity is endlessly enthusiastic
いたいなんて言い聞かせるんだ
Telling myself it hurts...
調子に乗ったらすぐ飽きられちゃうから あー！
If I get carried away, people will get bored, ah!
タイトなロープもどんとこいでっせ
Bring on tight ropes too, for sure!
すなわち特者生存ワンダランダDAY
That is, special survivor wonder-lander day!
楽しもう 面白がれること探し放題でっせ
Let's enjoy, finding fun things endlessly!
無限のフィールドで パニングしなくてもいい
In an infinite field, no need for panning
ど真ん中一直線
Straight down the middle!
つまりこれが僕の答えなんだ 胸を張れ！
In short, this is my answer. Stand tall!
今を生きるその意味を 明くる日も明くる日も確かめ進め！
Verify the meaning of living in the present day by day and move forward!
メモっておいて！
Make a note of it!
ホントはbaby 自信なんかないよ
Truth is, baby, I don't have confidence
ホントはbaby 不安ばっかで泣きそうだな
Truth is, baby, I'm full of anxiety and about to cry
でもねbaby くじけないって決めたの
But you know, baby, I decided not to give up
だからbaby 挑戦したいよ 未開の天地 無限のフィールドで！
So, baby, I want to challenge unknown realms in an infinite field!
前進上等！ちゃんと歓迎して
Advancing is top-notch! Welcome me properly
高まれ海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して
Rise, creation of sea and sky, be amazed properly
興奮しよう ボクが言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
Let's get excited! Since I say so, I'll make it real!
現実超えろ未来 あー！
Surpass reality, future, ah!
前進上等！ちゃんと歓迎して
Advancing is top-notch! Welcome me properly
高まれ海空創造 ちゃんと驚嘆して
Rise, creation of sea and sky, be amazed properly
興奮しよう ボクが言うんだもん 本当にするんだもん
Let's get excited! Since I say so, I'll make it real!
現実超えろ未来 あー！
Surpass reality, future, ah!
弱点も平気 スイッチでランチャー！
Weaknesses are fine too, launcher with a switch!
すなわち特者生存ワンダランダDAY
That is, special survivor wonder-lander day!
楽しもう 面白がれること探し放題でっせ
Let's enjoy, finding fun things endlessly!
無限のフィールドで パニングしなくてもいい
In an infinite field, no need for panning
ど真ん中一直線
Straight down the middle!
つまりこれが僕の答えなんだ 胸を張れ！
In short, this is my answer. Stand tall!
今を生きるその意味を 明くる日も明くる日も確かめ進め！
Verify the meaning of living in the present day by day and move forward!
パニングしなくてもいい (かなたーん！)
No need for panning! (Kanatan!)
ど真ん中一直線 (かなたーん！)
Straight down the middle! (Kanatan!)
つまりこれが僕の答えなんだ
In short, this is my answer
胸を張れ！今を生きるその意味を 明くる日も明くる日も確かめ進め！
Stand tall! Verify the meaning of living in the present day by day and move forward!
これが最強ワンダルダ！
This is the ultimate wonderer!
特者生存ワンダランダ！！
Special Survivor Wonder-la-der!!
わんつーで参拝！
Worship in one-two!
みこみこみこ！ (いぇーい！)
Miko miko miko! (Yay!)
マイネームイズエリート☆
My name is elite☆
ついに来たよ！お待たせ！
Finally here! Thanks for waiting!
待ちに待ったうへへへ
Waiting so long, uhehehe
電脳世界からやってきた
Coming from the cyber world,
ウザカワ系バーチャル巫女アイドル！
an annoying yet cute virtual miko idol!
わたしはそう！エリート！ (エリート？)
That's right, I am elite! (Elite?)
なんていったってエリート！ (えっへん！)
No matter what, elite! (Hmph!)
エリート巫女！？ エリートアイドル！？
Elite miko!? Elite idol!?
そんなの両方に決まってるじゃん！
Obviously both of those!
いじわるも 泣き虫も カミサマも！拝め！
Teasing ones, crybabies, and even gods! Worship them!
崇れば巫女パワーで 幸せ分けてあげてもいいんだよ？
If you revere me, I might share my miko power with you?
みこみこみこde ほにゃほにゃうにゃにゃにゃにゃ！ (にゃー！)
Miko miko miko de honyahonya unyanyanya! (Nya!)
さくらくるくるり さくらみこ (みこ！みこ！)
Sakura kurukururi Sakura Miko (Miko! Miko!)
みこみこみこde むにゃむにゃぐーぐーぐー…zz (ぐー！)
Miko miko miko de munyamunya guugugu...zz (Guu!)
明日からは本気だす！ (エリートですから！)
Starting tomorrow I'll get serious! (Because I'm elite!)
みこみこみこde ほにゃほにゃうにゃにゃにゃにゃ！ (にゃー！)
Miko miko miko de honyahonya unyanyanya! (Nya!)
金時はほにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃ…たぶん！
Kintoki is honyahanya... probably!
幸運の太鼓 ポンポコリリンリン！ (ポンポン！)
Drum of happiness, ponpokoririnrin! (Ponpon! )
みんな笑顔になあれ！
May everyone smile!
わんつーで参拝！ みこみこみこ！ (いぇーい！)
Worship in one-two! Miko miko miko! (Yay!)
ちょっとだけ休憩タイム マイペースだけど許してね！
Just a little break time, my pace, so forgive me!
実はこれは修行のうちです そんなわけは…あっバレたーっ！
Actually this is also training. There's no way... ah, I was caught!
わたしはそう！エリート！ (エリート？)
That's right, I am elite! (Elite?)
嘘じゃないよ？エリート！ (どやあ！)
No lies, elite! (Doya!)
エリート巫女！ エリートアイドル！ 今日もがんば 頑張っていきましょう！
Elite miko! Elite idol! Let's work hard today too!
ココロ模様 曇り色 雨の日も！？ 問題ない！巫女パワーで
State of mind: cloudy gray, even on rainy days!? No problem! With miko power
それ快晴パレード！ 騒いじおうよ！ (チャンネル登録してくれやぁ！)
It's a sunny parade! Let's make some noise! (Subscribe to the channel!)
みこみこみこde ほにゃほにゃうにゃにゃにゃにゃ！ (にゃー！)
Miko miko miko de honyahonya unyanyanya! (Nya!)
さくらくるくるり さくらみこ (みこ！みこ！)
Sakura kurukururi Sakura Miko (Miko! Miko!)
みこみこみこde むしゃむしゃむーぐーぐー (ぐー！)
Miko miko miko de mushyamushyamuuguugu (Guu!)
たい焼きめでたい焼き (ピーマンはno thank you！)
Taiyaki, celebratory taiyaki (Peppers are no thank you!)
みこみこみこde ほにゃほにゃうにゃにゃにゃにゃ！ (にゃー！)
Miko miko miko de honyahonya unyanyanya! (Nya!)
カミサマもほにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃ…たぶん！
Even gods are honyahanya... probably!
元気の呪文 巫女巫女舞舞舞！ (しゃんしゃん！)
Spell of energy, miko miko mai mai mai! (Shanshan!)
みんな笑顔になあれ！
May everyone smile!
わんつ、あ！ 間違いたぁーっ！ (ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！)
One, two, ah! I made a mistake! (Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!)
にゃっはろー！みんな楽しんでる？？ここからはスーパーみこみこタイム！
Nyahallo! Is everyone enjoying it?? From here is super miko miko time!
ぜーったいに遅れずについてきてね！みんなで一緒にお手を拝借！はい！
Make sure not to fall behind! Let's clap our hands together! Ready, go!
みーこ！みーこ！ (みーこ！みーこ！)
Miiko! Miiko! (Miiko! Miiko!)
みこはエリート！ (みこはエリート！) elite！ (elite！)
Miko is elite! (Miko is elite!) Elite! (Elite! )
エリート！エリート！イエーーー！！
Elite! Elite! Yeeeeaaah!!
ラストにもう一回張り切って行くよーっ！
Going all out once more for the last part!
みこみこみこde ほにゃほにゃうにゃにゃにゃにゃ！ (にゃー！)
Miko miko miko de honyahonya unyanyanya! (Nya!)
ワン、ツウ、で、参拝！
One, two, and bow!
みんな笑顔になあれ！
Make everyone smile!
ワン、ツウ、あ、間違えたーっ！
One, two—ah, I messed up!
にゃっはろー！みんな楽しんでる？？
Nyahallo! Is everyone having fun?
ここからはスーパーみこみこタイム！
From here on is Super Miko Miko Time!
絶対に遅れずに付いてきてね！？
Make sure you keep up without falling behind!
みんなで一緒に お手を拝借！はい！
Everyone together, lend me your hands! Here!
みーこ！みーこ！
Mii-ko! Mii-ko!
（みーこ！みーこ！）
みこはエリート！
Miko is elite!
elite!
みこはエリート！ イエーイ！
Miko is elite! Yay!
ラストにもう一回はりきって行くよーっ！
Let's go all out once more for the last part!
みこみこみこで ほにゃにゃにゃん
Miko Miko Miko, honyanyanyan
さくら、くら、くらり、さくらみこ
Sakura, kura, kurari, Sakura Miko
みこ、みこみこで みょんみょんみょん
Miko Miko Miko, myon myon myon
ミョーガは おたこ ぴょこぴょこ♪
Myoga is otako pyoko pyoko!
（チャームポイントですから！）
(Because it's my charm point!)
みこ、みこみこで ほにゃにゃにゃん
Miko Miko Miko, honyanyanyan
金時はほにゃにゃにゃん…たぶん！
Kintoki is honyanyanyan... probably!
みんな笑顔になあれ！
Make everyone smile!
ワン、ツウ、で、参拝！みこ、みこ、みこ、いえーい！
One, two, and bow! Miko, Miko, Miko, yay!
今日はみこ先輩来てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for coming today, Miko-senpai!
このマイネームイズエリートみこ先輩と一緒に歌いたいなって思ってたけど...
I wanted to sing "My Name is Elite" with Miko-senpai...
思っていたよりも早口でLamyはついていけず…ありがとうございました！
...but it was so fast I couldn't keep up! Thank you!
おしまい！みこみこみこ！いぇい☆
That's it! Miko Miko Miko! Yay☆
Say! ファンファーレ！
Say! Fanfare!
うーっ、こんこんっ！
Ugh, kon-kon!
せーのっ！ Are you ready?
Ready? Are you ready?
おっとひらいて お茶ですよ
Opening up, it's tea time
はい、どうぞ
Here you go
いつもの場所から 元気に出てのご挨拶
A cheerful greeting from our usual spot
おハコなんです！ 初めましてを
It's our specialty! Nice to meet you
始めましょう！
Let's begin!
おジャメに推して ゲットだスコスのス
Pushing in playfully, getting those suko-suko!
そんな毎日が愛しくて
Such everyday life is so precious
あれもこれも手を出し たくなり がちです
We tend to reach out for this and that
舞台とか ステージは まだまだ 恥ずかしいけど
Stages and platforms are still so embarrassing, but
支え合ってほらお届けますよ この声を
Supporting each other, look, we're delivering this voice
Say! ほら
Say! Look
その顔上げて
Lift up your face
みんなで手を取れば
If everyone takes hands together
Dive! まだまだ道の途中
Dive! Still on the way
世界を越えよう
Let's cross the world
Say! ほら
Say! Look
推しお仕事も
Even our oshi work
止まらない 全力ですから！
Never stops because we're going all out!
夢を書きかえたら 追いかけ続けよう
If we rewrite our dreams, let's keep chasing them
ともに 繋ぐ ファンファーレ！
Connecting together, fanfare!
Say! ファンファーレ！
Say! Fanfare!
うーっ、こんこんっ！
Ugh, kon-kon!
せーのっ！ Go! Go! Let's go!
Ready? Go! Go! Let's go!
ちょっとやらかした 時でも「ん、大丈夫！」
Even when we mess up, "Hmm, it's okay!"
気持ち切り替えて もっと違う昼下がりは
Switching moods, a different kind of afternoon
昼寝しよう！手押しおして
Let's take a nap! Pushing our hands
お腹が減ったら すぐモグモグと
When we get hungry, immediately munching
お茶の合間 すこな おやつで
Tea-time, sukona snacks
黒いあの娘は 一緒にして欲しいです
That black-haired girl wants to be together too
仲間のサラとお友達の皆さんっと
Comrade Sara and all our friends!
叶えたい思いは 言葉にしてひとつひとつ
The wishes we want to come true, turning them into words one by one
Say! ほら
Say! Look
その手を上げて
Raise your hands
みんなで輪になれば
If everyone forms a circle
Dive! まだまだ成長途中
Dive! Still growing on the way
問題ないでしょ？
No problem, right?
Say! ほら
Say! Look
明るく元気な 心が取り柄ですから！
Because our cheerful and bright spirit is our forte!
へこみがちな時も 輝き続けよう
Even during gloomy times, let's keep shining
ともに繋ぐ アンコール
Connecting together, encore!
Say! ファンファーレ！
Say! Fanfare!
うーっ、こんこんっ！
Ugh, kon-kon!
せーのっ！ Go! Go! Let's go!
Ready? Go! Go! Let's go!
なにもかもが新しくて 右も左も分からない時も
Even when everything is brand new and we don't know left from right
頑張れたのは 一人じゃないから
We were able to do our best because we weren't alone
ひとつひとつ応援が 形になって一歩ずつでも 私自身の仕組みが描いていくFuture
Each and every cheer takes shape, and step by step, my own mechanism draws the future
ほーっとひと息 お茶ですよ
Take a deep breath, it's time for tea.
はい、どーぞ！
Here you go!
いつもの場所から 元気にこなせーのでご挨拶
From our usual place, greeting you with high spirits.
おっほこんこんでぃーすよー！
Hello-kon-kon-dice to you!
始めましょう！
Let's get started!
おしゃべりをして ゲームと過ごす
Chatting away and spending time with games,
そんな毎日が 愛おしくて
every such day is so dear to me.
あれもこれも 手を出したくなり勝ちです
I tend to want to try all sorts of things,
歌とかステージは まだまだ恥ずかしいけど
though singing and stages are still a bit embarrassing.
支え合ってほら 届けますよ この声を
Supporting each other, look, I'll deliver this voice to you.
say!
ほら その顔上げて みんなで手を取れば
Hey, lift your face up, if we all take hands,
dive!
まだまだ道の途中 世界を越えよう
we're still on the path, let's cross the world.
say! ほら 推しお仕事も 止まらない 全力ですから！
Say! Look, oshi work never stops, because we're giving it our all!
夢を書きかえれば 追いかけ続けよう
If we rewrite our dreams, let's keep chasing them together,
ともに 繋ぐ ファンファーレ
connecting a fanfare together!
ちょっとやわらかい時でも
Even in gentle times,
気持ち 切り替えて ぽーっとしてしまう昼下がりは
switching gears, those dozy afternoons
ひるこんこんでぃーすよー！
are daytime kon-kon-dice to you!
背伸びをして お腹へったら すぐモグモグと
Stretching our backs, when hungry, we munch away right then,
お茶の合間す こんなおやつで
taking tea breaks with treats like these.
黒いあのコには 内緒にしてほしいです
Keep it a secret from that black-haired girl, please.
仲間の力と お友達のみなさんと
With our comrades' strength and all our friends,
叶えたい想いは 言葉にして 一つ一つ
turning every dream we want to fulfill into words, one by one.
say! ほら その手上げて みんなで輪になれば
Say! Look, if we raise our hands and form a circle,
dive! まだまだ成長途中 問題ないでしょ？
Dive! We're still growing, but that's no problem, right?
say! ほら 明るく元気になる心が 取り柄ですから！
Say! Look, our bright and cheerful hearts are our best trait!
へこみ気味な時も 輝き続けよう とともに 繋ぐ アンコール
Even when feeling down, let's keep shining, connecting an encore together.
あたしジャンクフードな思考回路
My thinking circuit is junk food,
咽せる退廃的な異常行動
choking on decadent, bizarre actions.
もどしたい！？ もどしたい！ もう痴態？ 不毛地帯！なら
Want it back?! Want it back! Already pathetic? If it's a barren wasteland!
人生リセットボタンぽちーw
Press the life reset button, lol.
人生にセットの段きちーw
Life's got a set of staircase jokes, lol.
品性にネット冗談きちーw
Online jokes hurting our dignity, lol.
人生リセットボタンぽちーw
Press the life reset button, lol.
人生リセットボタンぽち
Press the life reset button...
あたしジャンクフードな思考回路
My thinking circuit is junk food,
咽せる退廃的な異常行動
choking on decadent, bizarre actions.
もどしたい！？ もどしたい！ もう痴態？ 不毛地帯！なら
Want it back?! Want it back! Already pathetic? If it's a barren wasteland!
人生リセットボタンぽちーw
Press the life reset button, lol.
人生にセットの段きちーw
Life's got a set of staircase jokes, lol.
品性にネット冗談きちーw
Online jokes hurting our dignity, lol.
人生リセットボタンぽちーw
Press the life reset button, lol.
人生リセットボタンぽち
Press the life reset button...
あたしジャンクフードな思考回路
My thinking circuit is junk food,
咽せる退廃的な異常行動
choking on decadent, bizarre actions.
もどしたい！？ もどしたい！ もう痴態？ 不毛地帯！なら
Want it back?! Want it back! Already pathetic? If it's a barren wasteland!
人生リセットボタンぽちーw
Press the life reset button, lol.
人生にセットの段きちーw
Life's got a set of staircase jokes, lol.
品性にネット冗談きちーw
Online jokes hurting our dignity, lol.
人生リセットボタンぽちーw
Press the life reset button, lol.
人生リセットボタンぽち
Press the life reset button...
魅惑を隠す箱 秘宝に香る危険な
A box concealing allure, dangerously fragrant treasure,
dangerous marine smell
ahoy
これ開けたら君たちになんて言ってあげるべきかなぁ…？
What should I say to you guys when you open this...?
誘うガーネットの赤 極上の海賊の秘宝
The alluring red garnet, the ultimate pirate treasure,
それは私
that is me.
艶が溢れ漂う香りをどうかしら恐がらないで 開けてみて
Don't be afraid of the overflowing, alluring scent—try opening it.
Sexy世界一 Superビチビチブッちゃけ船長捕まえたい？
The sexiest in the world, super lively—frankly, want to catch the captain?
You’re gonna get the treasure Maybe tasting me
私の甘さが 欲しいでしょ
Do you want my sweetness?
秘宝の鍵を
The treasure's key...
優しく刺して
...gently pierce it in.
宝庫の扉マジで早く開けて
Open the vault's door, seriously, hurry up!
じれったい貴方の手 海図にこぼす甘いため息のTease
Your impatient hand spills sweet sighs of tease onto the nautical chart.
純紅のバラが しおれる前に
Before the crimson rose withers,
WE WILL SAIL THE SEVEN SEAS
SUMMER SUN SMILING WITH GLEE
SHINING OCEAN OF MARINE
Now please grant my dearest dream Open up this box
Open it right now or i will scream
あぁぁぁぁぁぁぁぁぁ！！！
Or else... Aaaaaah!
鳴く子も黙る naughty 悩ましいビーム
A naughty, alluring beam that silences crying children.
君たちももう我慢できないでしょ？
You guys can't hold back anymore, right?
You’re gonna own the pleasure Maybe love of me?
私のすべてを手に入れて
Get your hands on all of me.
金銀財宝 弾き稼得でしょ
Treasure and riches are easily earned, right?
しわしわになっちゃう 誰か助けて
I'm shriveling up, someone help me!
マジで遠慮しすぎ君たち何考えてんの
Seriously, you guys are holding back too much, what are you thinking?
わかってんだろ欲望だから今すぐ開けてよ
You know it's desire, so open it right now!
たからばこ open up this box
Treasure box (open up this box).
あなたを待つガーネット…
The garnet waiting for you...
魅惑を隠す箱
A box that hides allure,
秘宝に香る危なげな
giving off a dangerous scent of treasure.
dangerous marine smell
❤Ahoy❤
❤️ Ahoy ❤️
(これ開けたら君たちにななんて言ってあげるべきかな…？)
(If I open this, what should I say to you guys...?)
「探してたのはせ・ん・じ・ょ・お？」うーん...
"Were you looking for a cap... cap... captain?" Hmm...
「あいん❤そんなにがっついちゃダメだぞ❤」かな？
"Aha ❤️ Don't get so greedy, okay ❤️" Or maybe?
「お宝より魅力的な”モノ”見つけちゃった…？」いいじゃない❤
"Did you find something more attractive than treasure...?" Isn't that nice? ❤️
誘うガーネットの赤 極上の海賊の秘宝
The red of enticing garnet, the ultimate pirate's treasure.
それは私
That is me.
艶が溢れ漂う 香りをどうか怖がらないで
Please don't be afraid of the overflowing, alluring scent—
開けてみて
just try opening it.
(アッハッハッハ…❤)
(Ah-ha-ha-ha... ❤️)
Sexy世界一 Superピチピチ
The sexiest in the world, super fresh!
ぶっちぎり船長捕まえたいでしょ？
You want to catch the runaway captain, right?
You’re gonna get the treasure
You're gonna get the treasure
Maybe tasting me
私の甘さが欲しいんでしょ
You want my sweetness, don't you?
(Ah-hoy!! Da-ba-da-boi)
秘宝の鍵を 優しい挿して
Softly insert the key to the treasure...
宝庫の扉マジで早く開けて
Open the treasure vault door for real, quickly!
(❤Ahoy❤)
(❤️ Ahoy ❤️)
泣く子も黙る Naughty 悩殺ビーム
The crying children quiet down with this naughty seduction beam!
キミたちももう我慢できなくない？
Aren't you guys unable to hold back anymore too?
You’re gonna own the pleasure
You're gonna own the pleasure
Maybe love of me?
私の全てを手に入れて
Take all of me into your hands!
金銀財宝は
Gold, silver, and treasure
走って稼いでしょ？
earned by running, right?
しわしわになっちゃう
I'm getting all wrinkly,
誰か助けて
somebody help me!
マジで遠慮しすぎ
Seriously, you're way too polite—
キミたち何考えてんの
what are you guys thinking?
分かってるんだわ 渇望 だから今すぐ開けてよ
I know you're craving it, so open it right now!
宝箱 (Open up this box)
Treasure box (Open up this box)
貴方を待つガーネット…
The garnet awaiting you...
鈴の音響く
The sound of bells echoing
深い夜とお月さま
through the deep night and the moon.
今宵宴の用意を
Prepare for tonight's banquet,
高笑いこらえ
suppressing a proud laugh.
鳴呼、式神を連れ立って
Ah, bringing along the shikigami,
戯れに興じるのだ
we revel in playful sport.
流れゆく時を想う
Pondering the flowing time,
消えゆく日々ならば
if these days are fading away,
この刹那さえ美しくしよう
let us make even this fleeting moment beautiful.
咲かせて空高く そっと
Make it bloom high in the sky, softly.
はんなり はんなり 夢花火
Gracefully, gracefully, dream fireworks,
ふんわり ふんわり 願うのは
softly, softly, what we wish for
現世の思い出だけ
is only the memories of this fleeting world.
ずっと 幾年 時を重ねて
Always, piling up years and time,
巡り会う世は情け
a world where we meet by fate is full of empathy.
とこしえに余は
For eternity, I
歌って笑っていたいのだ
want to sing and laugh forever.
静けさ満ちる
Silence fills the air,
浮かぶ三つ影法師
three shadows floating.
今宵祭りの後よ
After tonight's festival,
寂しさ抑え
suppressing the loneliness.
鳴呼、皆どもを想いながら
Ah, thinking of everyone,
まどろみへ委ねるのだ
surrendering to slumber.
生まれては弾き消える
Born, then popping and vanishing,
泡沫の調べは
the melody of foam bubbles—
その一瞬も大切にしよう
let's cherish even that single instant.
聞かせて鮮やかに そっと
Let it be heard vividly, softly.
きんなり きんなり 夢花火
Dazzlingly, dazzlingly, dream fireworks,
ひっそり ひっそり 祈るのは
quietly, quietly, what we pray for
永遠の楽しさだけ
is only eternal joy.
ずっと 幾年 時を重ねて
Always, piling up years and time,
想い出す夜はあわれ
nostalgic nights are sorrowful.
こころゆくまで 踊って騒いでいたいのだ
Wanting to dance and make merry until my heart is full.
風吹きれば 夢のまにまに
If the wind should blow at the whim of dreams,
行く宛のない 僕は歌う
without a place in mind, I'll sing.
夢花火 空の彼方へ
Lighting up the sky, dreams of fireworks so high,
ずっと ずっと 夢を見ていた
always, it's been, a neverending dream for me.
やっと やっと 君を見つけた
Finally, finally, I've found my way here to you.
ふんわりふんわり 祈るのは
Gently, gently, praying for
現世の楽しさだけ
just the joy of this fleeting world.
いつまでも 幾年時を重ねて
Forever, piling up the years,
巡り合う世は情け 忘れないように
may we never forget the grace of meeting.
とことしえには 港と笑っていたいのよ
Forevermore, I want to keep smiling by your harbor.
風、一つ 染まっている 音をたなびかせ
Wind, one, letting the coloring sound flutter away,
流れ出す 朝焼けの空を飛んでいく
flowing out and flying across the morning glow sky.
聞こえた 震えている声の君は誰だろう
I heard it—who is that trembling voice?
なんでかな 会いたくなったんだ 会えるかな
Why did I suddenly want to see you? Can I see you?
夢、一つ 鞄のポケットに忍ばせて
Dream, one, tucked away in the pocket of a bag,
鐘、一つ 始まりの朝に遠く響く
bell, one, echoing far into the opening morning.
思い出す 結んだ指に残った温度は 今もまだ 青く残っている 褪せぬまま
Remembering: the warmth left on our intertwined fingers is still left blue now, without fading.
「鳥や、雲じゃないから 飛んでいくのは、無理だね」
"Because we're not birds or clouds, it's impossible to fly away."
それだったら 歩き出してみよう そうやって
"If so, let's try walking. Like that,"
描いた今日を通り越して
jumping over the day we drew,
明日はもっと君のそばへ 前へ、そう前へ 少しずつ進んでいく
tomorrow is closer to you, more forward, moving forward little by little.
一歩、五十歩、百歩 踏み出して
One step, fifty steps, a hundred steps, stepping out,
揺らめいている君が 青く滲む 青く滲む 綺麗に
the swaying you bleeding blue, bleeding blue, beautifully.
会いに行こう 会いにいこう 今すぐ
I'm going to see you right now.
波、白く さざめく音に耳を立てて
Waves, white, prick up your ears to the rustling sound,
赤く、青く、夕映えの空 昇る星
red, blue, a star rising in the sunset sky.
不思議と不安な旅も怖くないから
Even an uneasy journey is not scary, so
手を振ってうつむかないように歩いていく
walking so you don't wave goodbye and look down.
「憧れても、願っても 誰にもなれないな」
"Even if you admire it or wish for it, you can't become anyone."
それだったら 自分になってみよう そうやって
"If so, let's try becoming ourselves. Like that,"
目指した今日を飛び越えて
jumping over the day we aimed for,
明日はきっと会えるから じゃあね、そうしたらね 一緒に何を話そう
tomorrow we will surely meet. See you, if so, what shall we talk about together?
一歩、五十歩、百歩 重ね合って
One step, fifty steps, a hundred steps, overlapping,
紡いでいく時間が 溶けていく 溶けていく それでもいつかは
the time we weave melts away... but still someday
夢が終わるなら それでも良いかな
if the dream ends, is that still okay?
君がいるなら 世界の中で
If you are here, within this world,
出会えた君が 理由になったら それでも良いかな
you whom I met becoming the reason—is that still okay?
一人の今日を飛び越えて 描いた今日を通り越して
Jumping over a single today, skipping today that I drew,
明日はもっと君のそばへ 前へ、そう前へ 少しずつ進むよ
tomorrow is closer to you, more forward, moving forward little by little.
一歩、五百歩、千歩 繰り返して
One step, five hundred steps, one thousand steps, repeatedly,
指に触れる君が 青く滲む 青く滲む 綺麗に
you touching my fingers bleeding blue, beautifully.
いつまでもそばにいて 良いかな 良いかな 良いかな
Can I stay by your side forever? Is that okay?
contas hale ’ ilia on shallys
contas hale'ilia on shallys
animu mita potima i ji'ulyc
zi clocs oc nolez dinau key tyn
hap'a myukil sha lu be'iru
yai didi la leu minas sak'chwa
dig nau e minas liga dia
dishi di las weina vetic as
di mi wo ilaj molof hap'a
contas hale'ilia on shallys
animu mita potima i ji'ulyc
alovia tolum stulia
non tocia stulia
contas hale'ilia on shallys
animu mita potima i ji'ulyc
zi clocs oc nolez dinau key tyn
hap'a myukil sha lu be'iru
es tuna ligali vidia
fala to st lumia diz lomo
kuls winia nina i ji'ulyc
menelasm oc lulu
dili lalu pi puru no do muru
fal'ma in vila le mam silli fri
o no mabul vaniro undal'ne
dina wia salame
te can't mila lila, ah
hafit lasimiya
fimola shelo niconia
dimi woi plop'po neona
fimola shelo lala
hafit lasimiya
fimola shelo niconia
dimi woi plop'po neona
fimola shelo lala
contas hale'ilia on shallys
animu mita potima i ji'ulyc
zi clocs oc nolez dinau key tyn
hap'a myukil sha lu be'iru
es tuna ligali vidia
fala to st lumia diz lomo
kuls winia nina i ji'ulyc
menelasm oc lulu
dili lalu pi puru no do muru
何？
What?
何なに真顔？
What's with that straight face?
真顔かい、雪民さん！
A straight face, Yukimin?
ラミーのこんな熱いほよよラヴキッスが
Lamy's burning hot, squishy love kiss...
も、も、も、も...ってことだね！
...is, m-m-m-m... so yeah!
えー、茶番はこれぐらいにして、
Um, let's wrap up this silly skit,
さりげなく衣装チェンジもいたしました！
and I casually changed into a new outfit too!
みんな、ほらライブ衣装とかね、雪民さんも見てると思うけど、
Everyone, see, my live outfit and all, I'm sure you Yukimin are watching,
まさかね、ラミーの雪民さんこの水着姿見慣れてるなんかいないよね？
surely none of you Yukimin are used to seeing Lamy in this swimsuit form, right?
いないよね？
Right?
もっと見たいでしょ？
You want to see more, don't you?
いいんだよ、見ても！
It's okay to look!
見てもいいんだよ雪民さんほら！
It's okay to look, Yukimin, see!
こんな、こんな、こんな間近で雪民さん見れるんだよ！よかったね！
You get to see Lamy up close like this! Aren't you lucky?
ってことでね、ここからはラミーのソロパートに戻りますので、雪民さんはあっちで応援してください！
So anyway, from here on we're back to Lamy's solo part, so you Yukimin go cheer over there!
それでは皆さん聞いてください。「かくしん的☆めたまるふぉ～ぜっ！」
Now then, everyone, please listen to "Kakushinteki☆Metamaruphose!"
U・M・R！U・M・R！
U-M-R! U-M-R!
UMAじゃないよ う・ま・る！
I'm not a UMA - Umaru!
U・M・R！U・M・R！
U-M-R! U-M-R!
UMAじゃないよ
I'm not a UMA
いつだって 全身全霊 遊び倒せ！
Always giving it my all, playing to the max!
もっと もっと 楽しめよ 乙女
Have even more fun, maiden!
みんなに気付かれないように
So that no one notices,
いざ、ゆけ！干物妹ライフ
Now go! N.E.E.T. sister life!
お気に入りのフードかぶり
Putting on my favorite hood,
今日も今日とてゴロゴロして
Slacking off again today just like always,
大好物のポテチを手 に
With my favorite potato chips in hand,
パソコンとにらめっこしよう
Staring down my PC screen.
立てば芍薬 座れば牡丹
Graceful as a peony, lovely as a tree peony,
歩く姿は百合の花
Walking like a white lily,
誰もが羨む 完璧JK
The perfect high school girl everyone envies!
ほら玄関くぐったら変身だ！
See, once through the door, it's time to transform!
さぁ グータラしよう♪
Now, let's laze around♪
「食う！寝る zzz 遊ぶ♪」の3連コンボ
The triple combo of "eat, sleep zzz, and play♪"
ずっと ずっと ゲームは友達
Forever and ever, games are my friends.
お兄ちゃんは厳しい けど
Big brother is strict, but
きっと きっと 許してくれちゃうの
I'm sure, I'm sure he'll forgive me.
ワガママ放題は 「大好き」の裏返し
Acting spoiled is just the flip side of "I love you".
U・M・R！U・M・R！UMAじゃないよ う・ま・る！
U-M-R! U-M-R! I'm not a UMA - Umaru!
外では猫をかぶり
Putting on a facade outside,
今日も明日も演じるのです
I'll keep acting today and tomorrow too.
大好評の笑顔を武器に
Using my popular smile as a weapon,
トモダチにバレないように
So my friends won't find out.
立てば2頭身 座ればまんまる
Standing, two-headed; sitting, round,
歩く姿もちんちくりん
Walking with chubby little steps,
誰でも癒せる 愛嬌マスコット！
A charming mascot that heals everyone!
さぁ 限界超えるまでパーティないっ！
Now, party on till we break our limits!
歌の始まりだァー！
The song begins!
みんなのおかげで 雪花ラミー 3周年でも迎えることができました！
Thanks to everyone, I was able to celebrate Yukihana Lamy's 3rd anniversary!
4年目もたくさんたくさん頑張っていくので、よろしくお願いします！
I'll keep working hard in my 4th year too, so please look forward to it!
可憐で優雅な 女のコ演じてみても
Even if I act like a dainty, graceful girl,
お兄ちゃんだけは 騙せない
I can't fool big brother.
嫌われたくないもん
I don't want him to hate me!
素直に言えない
I can't honestly say
「ありがとう」 態度で示そう
"Thank you"—I'll show it through my attitude.
…だぁ！前言撤回！
...Wait! Retracting that statement!
ああもーイイじゃん！お兄ちゃんなんて知らないっ！
Oh whatever! I don't care about big brother!
なんつって！
Just kidding!
一心同体 2人でひとつ
One in body and soul, the two of us as one,
だって だって それが兄妹でしょ？
Because, because that's what siblings are, right?
一蓮托生 2人きりの運命共同体
Sharing the same fate, a duo bound by destiny.
今日だって 自由奔放 笑い飛ばせ！
Today too, live freely and laugh it off!
もっと もっと 楽しんだもん勝ち
He who enjoys it more wins!
天真爛漫スマイルで
With an innocent, carefree smile,
ぎゅっと ぎゅっと 心をつかんじゃうの
I'll capture your heart tightly, tightly.
やりたい放題は 信頼の裏返し？
Doing whatever I want is a sign of trust?
U・M・R！U・M・R！UMAじゃないよ う・ま・る！
U-M-R! U-M-R! I'm not a UMA - Umaru!
はい、おしまいっ！
Yup, that's it!
はーい、ということで皆さん聴いていただきました、かくしん的☆めたまるふぉ～ぜっ！
Ha-ii, so everyone, that was "Kakushinteki☆Metamaruphose!"
え、このあとの流れはみんな これだからわかるよね？
Well, you all know how this goes next, right?
これだからわかるよね？
You get it, right?
そう！ラミィのオリジナル新曲歌いまーす！いえーい！
That's right! Lamy's brand-new original song, let's sing! Yay!
えーということでね、みんな聞いてください！
And with that everyone, please listen!
ラミィ ラブ フェスタ！
Lamy Love Festa!
由々しき事態の絵面
A grave situation in appearance,
気付けば溢れるラヴみ
Before you notice, overflowing love,
(Love me!)
恥じらい捨てるが正解
Discarding bashfulness is the correct answer.
気付きつつもご愛嬌
Though realizing it, it's just cute charm.
(Ding-dong!)
こんばみです！お酒と雪民をこよなく愛する5期生、
Good evening! The 5th gen member who loves alcohol and Yukimin dearly,
肝っ玉雪花ラミィです！
the gutsy Yukihana Lamy!
朝昼夜といろんな時間に配信してるのでお好きな時間に会いに来てね！
Streaming at all hours of morning, day, and night, so come meet me whenever you like!
...あ、もう全然間に合わない！！！
...Ah, I'm totally not going to make it in time!!!
雪の国からやってきました！
I've come from the snow country!
間違いと言われようとも、雪女じゃないです！
Even if people call it a misunderstanding, I'm not a snow woman!
というのは言い訳なんです
That's just an excuse,
冬は苦手なんです…
I'm actually bad with winter...
さてさて ここいらで とりあえず いっぱい しょしょお待ち
Well, for now, wait just a moment with a drink!
パッパッラッパ 酔いはじめ
Pa-pa-ra-ppa, starting to get drunk,
みなさんご一緒に！
Everyone together!
今宵酔いどれで さあ 飲みあかそう！
Tonight, let's get drunk and drink the night away!
ラミィのセカイへ おいでおませ
Come on over to Lamy's world,
ここは天国かユートピア☆
This is heaven or utopia☆
あっちにこっちに 手をばぼばぼ
Reaching out here and there, wa-wa-wa,
大きな夢 叶えましょう バンザイからの丸からのバツ ここは
Let's make big dreams come true! From banzai to circle to cross, this is
ひょうきんなシャングリラ☆
A comical Shangri-La☆
ツッコミだって大喜利だって お手のもと
Tsukkomi or ogiri are a piece of cake,
世界中 幸せをお届けします
Delivering happiness all over the world!
(満面笑顔 ありがとね!)
With a full smile, thank you!
こんな声だってどうだい？
How is a voice like this?
耳の奥 響くノイズ
Noise echoing deep in your ears,
そそろそ やめていいかい？
Can I stop soon?
ここでもう一度のやめなさい！
Once again here, "Stop right there!"
黒歴史なら 忘れ去って
If it's dark history, forget all about it,
もうラミィのライブはゼロなんだよ！
Lamy's live has zero left!
これ以上やめなーい、やめろ、やめなさい！！
Stop it already, stop, stop it!!
おっと 酔いが回ってきた
Oops, the alcohol is getting to my head,
抜き足 差し足 忍び足
Stealthy steps, tip-toe steps,
とりあえず そろーり そろーり
For now, slowly, slowly,
グルグル回る 世界で 絡まる ベロベロ バイラレル
Spinning round and round in the world, tangling up, slur-slur, parallel,
なんか舌が回らないけろ…？
Somehow my tongue isn't working...?
咲いて 乱れて 雪月花
Blooming, fluttering, snow-moon-flower,
ここは 天国か ユートピア☆
This is heaven or utopia☆
ニッチもサッチも 手をばぼばぼ
No matter what, hands wa-wa-wa,
世界中 二人占めしましょう 飲んで飲まれて 雪よ酔い
Let's keep the world to ourselves, drinking and getting drunk on snow,
ここは 絢爛な アルカディア☆
This is a gorgeous Arcadia☆
花鳥だって風月だって叶わない
Neither flowers, birds, wind, nor moon can compare,
世界中 ラミィ色に染め上げよう！
Let's dye the whole world in Lamy's color!
ほらほら
Come on, come on,
まだまだここから！行くよ？せーの！ギターカモーーーン！！！！
Still from here! Here we go? Ready, set! Guitar caaame-on!!!!
推してくれたから
Because you supported me,
頑張ってこれました！
I was able to work hard!
ホントありがとね！
Thank you so much!
今度はラミィが背中押してあげるから
Next time, Lamy will push your back,
ずっとずっとそばにいてね♪
Please stay by my side forever and ever♪
泣きたいときこそ Lamy＊Love＊Fest☆
Especially when you want to cry, Lamy＊Love＊Fest☆
ラミィのセカイは終わらない
Lamy's world never ends,
ここは 天国か ユートピア☆
This is heaven or utopia☆
明日だって明後日だって Happy Happy Days!
Tomorrow and the day after, Happy Happy Days!
幸せにしよう バンザイからの丸からのバツ ここは
Let's make you happy! From banzai to circle to cross, this is
最高のシャングリラ☆
The best Shangri-La☆
大雨だって大雪だって虹になれ
Even heavy rain or snow, become a rainbow,
世界中 明日も元気になれ！
May the whole world be energetic tomorrow too!
みんな大好きです！
I love you all!
今日も今日とて元気をお届けしますっ♪
Today as well, I'll deliver energy to you♪
雪花ラミィ活動3周年記念記念グッズ＆記念ボイス ご予約受付中です！
Yukihana Lamy's 3rd Anniversary commemorative goods & voice collection are now available for pre-order!
抱き枕カバーは、リン☆ユウママに写真をとってもらいました！
For the body pillow cover, Rin Yuu-mama took photos for us!
裏と表でガラッと雰囲気が変わるけど、雪民さんはどっちが好きかな？
The vibe changes drastically between front and back, which one do Yukimin prefer?
そして、むーらん先生にイラストを描いていただきました！ラミィとお揃いマグカップ！
And, Moolan-sensei drew the illustration! Lamy's matching mug!
持ち手が取っ手になっていて、すごくかわいいでしょ？
The handle is designed as a knob, isn't it super cute?
「大好きな君専用」っていうのは、ラミィが君に使ってほしくて書いたんだからね！
Saying "exclusively for my dearest you" means Lamy wrote that because she wants you to use it!
そして、ラミィとお揃い雪民スリッパ！
And matching Yukimin slippers with Lamy!
ラミィが履いてるのは大根のスリッパだけど、雪民さんは雪民さん専用のスリッパをお揃いで仲良く履こうね。
Lamy wears daikon radish slippers, but Yukimins can wear matching slippers made just for you.
そして記念ボイスはシチュエーションボイス、「同棲彼女の甘々おやすみボイス」となっております！
And the commemorative voice is a situation voice, "Cohabitating Girlfriend's Super Sweet Goodnight Voice"!
ラミィの抱き枕をぎゅっと抱きながら聞いてね。
Listen to it while hugging Lamy's body pillow tight.
そして、活動3周年記念フルセットはこちら！
And here is the 3rd Anniversary Full Set!
特典ボイスは同棲彼女の甘々お目覚めボイスとなっています！
The bonus voice is "Cohabitating Girlfriend's Super Sweet Wake-Up Voice"!
記念ボイスの続きの話になってるので、こっちもぜひぜひ聞いてね。
It continues the story from the commemorative voice, so be sure to listen to this one too.
そしてチェキ風ブロマイドカードは雪民さんに寝てる間に隠し撮りされちゃったラミィの1枚！
And the cheki-style bromide card is a photo of Lamy secretly taken by a Yukimin while she was sleeping!
ちょっと恥ずかしいけど、飾ってくれると嬉しいな。
It's a bit embarrassing, but I'd be happy if you display it.
それではみんな、ここまで見てくれて本当にありがとう！
Well then everyone, thank you so much for watching this far!
みんなが押してくれたから、雪花ラミィが3周年を迎えることができました！
Thanks to everyone's support, Yukihana Lamy was able to celebrate her 3rd anniversary!
これからもたくさんたくさん頑張っていくので、みんな応援よろしくね！
I'll keep working hard moving forward, so everyone please keep supporting me!
雪民さん、だーいすき！ラヴ・マッ・チュ！
Yukimins, I love you so much! Love-mah-chu!